A Guide to the Pocantico Hills photographs, Series 1006 FA450
Rockefeller Archive Center
Pocantico Hills photographs, Series 1006
1880-1982 (Bulk: 1909-1939)
1909-1939
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, John D., III (John Davison) (1906-1978)
Rockefeller, John D., Jr. (John Davison) (1874-1960)
FA450
11.3 Cubic Feet 36 containers. Extent is approximate.
Approximately 1,545 prints, contact sheets and slides.
Arrangement
Rockefeller family photographic holdings are arranged into the following series: Rockefeller family and Avery family photographs, Series 1001. William Avery Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1002. John D. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1003. William Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1004. John D. Rockefeller Jr. family photographs, Series 1005. Pocantico Hills photographs, Series 1006. John D. Rockefeller 3rd family photographs, Series 1007. Nelson A. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1008. Laurance S. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1009. David Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1010.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
This collection primarily consists of interior and exterior photographs of Kykuit through the years (Kykuit I, Kykuit II and Kykuit III) including construction and remodeling shots, as well as the surrounding grounds including the gardens, sculpture, golf course, and other estate residences and buildings. There is also a small selection of aerial views, as well as historic photographs of the village, school, railroad, and Union Chuch of Pocantico Hills.
Arrangement
The Pocantico Hills photographs are arranged in Subseries by Format: Prints, Albums, and Oversized. There is also a separate subseries for the Kykuit Photograph Project.
Photographs
- Pocantico Hills photographs, 1880-1982 (Bulk: 1909-1939); 1909-1939; 1006; 11.3 Cubic Feet
  Arrangement
  This series contains 1 subseries:
  1006C Kykuit Photograph Project.
  For ease of access the material is further arranged by:
  Prints (Boxes P 1, P 2, P 3, etc.). Albums (Boxes A 1, A 2, A 3, etc.) Oversized (Boxes: O 1, O 2, O 3, C 1, C 2, C 3, etc.).
  - Prints, 6.08 Cubic Feet 16 letter document boxes
    - Pocantico Hills, 31 prints (Box P 158, Folder 47)
    - Buildings, 1911-1940; 18 prints (Box P 118)
    - Buildings - Garage, 1902-1914; 12 prints (Box P 118)
    - Buildings - Playhouse, 28 prints (Box P 118)
    - Buildings - Tea House - Dedication, 1962 December 8; 52 prints and contact sheets (Box P 158, Folder 48)
    - Construction, 1928-1932; 114 prints (Box P 119)
    - Employees, 4 prints (Box P 119)
    - Entrance, 1940; 3 prints (Box P 119)
    - Gardens, 1911-1938; 63 prints (Box P 120)
    - Gardens, 1911-1922; 51 prints (Box P 121)
    - Gardens - R.W. Grange, Jr. Album, 1907-1909; 28 prints (Box P 122)
    - Golf Course, 1 print (Box P 123)
    - Grounds, 1928-1966; 21 prints (Box P 123)
    - Historical Markers, 1976; 4 prints (Box P 123)
    - Abeyton Lodge, 16 prints (Box P 123)
    - Homes - Japanese Tea House, 1976; 1 print (Box P 124)
    - Homes - Kent House, 7 prints (Box P 124)
    - Homes - Kykuit I (Parsons-Wentworth house), 1893-1902; 13 prints (Box P 124)
    - Homes - Kykuit II exterior, 1907-1911; 25 prints (Box P 124)
    - Homes - Kykuit II interior, 1909; 23 prints (Box P 125)
    - Homes - Kykuit III exterior, 1911-1964; 26 prints (Box P 125)
    - Homes - Kykuit III interior, 1959-1963; 13 prints (Box P 126)
    - Homes - Kykuit III, 1 print (Box P 158, Folder 49)
    - Homes - Milton House, 3 prints (Box P 126)
    - Homes - R.W. Grange, Jr. Album, 1907-1909; 30 prints (Box P 126)
    - Homes - Furniture, 26 prints (Box P 127)
    - Homes - Saportas House, 3 prints (Box P 127)
    - Properties, 5 prints (Box P 127)
    - Railroads, 1880-1930s; 21 prints (Box P 127)
    - Sculpture, 1914-1966; 52 prints (Box P 128)
    - Sculpture, 1977; 14 prints, color. (Box P 158, Folder 50)
    - Tarrytown, 1962; 1 print (Box P 128)
    - Union Church, 1922-1967; 43 prints and contact sheets (Box P 129)
    - Views, 23 prints (Box P 129)
    - Vehicles, 1899-1971; 62 prints (Box P 130)
    - Village, 1930 May 13; 59 prints (Box P 131)
      Scope and Contents
      Survey of Pocantico Hills Estate
    - Village, 1892-1912, 1930, 1976; 53 prints (Box P 132)
      Continuation of "Survey of Pocantico Hills Estate (1930)" and additional photographs
  - Albums, 1.7 Cubic Feet 8 containers
    - "Bridle Paths, Pocantico Hills Estate", 25 prints (Box A 1)
    - Grounds - "Supplement to draft of report and preliminary plans for the Pocantico Hills Properties", by Community Research and Development, Inc., 1962 July; 2 copies.; 9 prints and maps with a duplicate copy. (Box A 3)
    - Grounds - Roads and Bridges on Kykuit Estate, 31 prints (Box A 4)
    - Homes - Kykuit - "Photographs of Kykuit, 1909 and 1913", 1-34, 1909, 1913 (Box A 5)
    - Homes - Kykuit - "Photographs of Kykuit, 1909 and 1913", 35-74, 1909, 1913 (Box A 6)
    - Homes - Kykuit III - Construction, 1911; 17 prints (Box A 2)
    - Homes - Kykuit III - Interior, 1963 May; 32 prints (Box A 7)
    - Homes - Playhouse, 32 prints (Box A 8)
  - Oversized, 1.92 Cubic Feet 7 containers
    - Buildings, 5 prints (Box O 1)
    - Entrance, 4 prints (Box O 1)
    - Homes - Kykuit - Guest House, 1959; 9 prints (Box O 4)
      With associated correspondence.
    - Homes - Kykuit - Aerial Views, 12 prints (Box C 6, Box O 6)
    - Homes - Kykuit II (Box C 6)
    - Sculpture, 1915; 12 prints (Box O 2)
    - Sculpture - Placement, 5 prints (Box O 5)
    - Vehicles, 8 prints (Box O 3)
    - Views, 7 prints (Box O 3)
    - Village, 1887; 1 print (Box O 3)
      Railroad station and Foley's Inn
  - Kykuit Photograph Project, 1982; 1006C; 1.61 Cubic Feet 5 containers
    - Oversized, 1.61 Cubic Feet 5 containers
      - Contact sheets, 32 contact sheets and duplicates (Box O 7)
      - Grounds, Gardens (color prints), 40 prints (Box O 8)
      - Grounds, Gardens (color prints), 48 prints (Box O 9)
      - Interior (color slides), 1982; 100 slides (approximate) (Box O 10)
      - Exterior (color slides), 1982; 100 slides (approximate) (Box O 11)